Guide to the Albert Léon Guérard Papers, 1909-1959 M0016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Albert Léon Guérard Papers,
1909-1959
M0016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
1.5 Linear feet
Guérard, Albert Léon, 1880-1959.
Scope and Content Note
Letters mainly to Guérard from authors, educators, and statesmen. Includes correspondence relating to world government; pamphlets and correspondence on "auxiliary languages"; and letters to his publishers, Scribner, and T. Fisher Irwin (England). Correspondents include Gertrude Atherton, Bernard Berenson, Van Wyck Brooks, D. W. Brogan, James Branch Cabell, Ernest Dimnet, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, Herbert Hoover, Julian S. Huxley, David Starr Jordan, Thomas Mann, André Maurois, H. L. Mencken, Lewis Mumford, and André Siegfried.
Stanford's Albert Guérard manuscript collection reveals the former professor to be the "foremost authority in this country on auxiliary languages," as he is described in the International Auxiliary Language Association General Report of 1945, included among his papers.
The Collection, gift of his wife in 1960, includes:
Two boxes of letters, mostly to him and a few with carbon copies of his replies. There are letters from Albert Camus, Thomas Mann, Bertrand Russell, H.G. Wells, and Mark Van Doren, among others.
4 boxes of pamphlets concerning international languages-- many in French, his native language.
dictionaries, course outlines
articles explaining and promoting International Languages
comparison of texts of the International Languages
5 manilla envelopes
selected letters on Public Issues, particularly World War II
63 letters from David Star Jordan
letters to his publisher, Scribner
couple of his last manuscripts
notes on his literature readings in preparation for the Agregation, French equivalent of the Doctorate degree.
Guérard, born in Paris in 1880, came to the United States in 1906 to teach at Williams College. He taught at Stanford from 1907 to 1946 when he retired, except for 12 years between 1913 and 1925 when he was at Rice University and served in the war. He died in Palo Alto, Nov. 14, 1959.
He is the author of 29 books; the most important were Testament of a Liberal, France: A Short History, French Civilization in the 19th Century, and Europe Free and United.
Stanford News and Publications issued a release after Guérard's death quoting Guérard as having described himself: "A Frenchman by birth, an American by choice; a teacher of literature by profession, a philosopher and historian by inclination; and a staunch advocate of world government by conviction."
Guérard's collection of papers and letters reveal him as the man he described himself to be: Frenchman, American, literature professor, philosopher, historian and internationalist.
They show his personality, interests and opinions
They are a commentary on the times, the current literature, politics and religious issues
They describe the development of an International Language, the behind-the-scene decisions and struggles, through:
pamphlets about the history of Esperanto
publications by the International Auxiliary Language Association concerning their attempts to decide on and promote an International Language
Guérard's papers, notes and correspondence
Biographical Note
Albert Léon Guérard was born in Paris in 1880 and was educated at the University of Paris, the University of London and the Sorbonne.
In 1906 Mr. Guérard came to the United States and taught one year at Williams College in Massachusetts. Then he joined the staff at Stanford as assistant professor of French in 1907.
In 1913 he went to Rice Institute at Houston, Texas, where he taught until 1924. In 1925 he went to UCLA and then was appointed professor of General Literature at Stanford.
He was the author of 20 books, essays, poems, autobiography, besides numerous articles for magazines. He was interested in creating an international language. Professor Guérard died at his home on the Stanford University campus November 13, 1959.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs Guérard and Albert Guérard, Jr., 1960.
Access Restrictions
None.
- CORRESPONDENCE IN (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. Aldington, Richard, Nov 26, 1926.
  - 2. Angell, Norman, Aug 12, 1913.
  - 3. Atherton, Gertrude, May 4, 1922.
  - 4. Atherton, Gertrude, N.D.
  - 5. Atherton, Gertrude, N.D.
  - 6. Babbitt, Irving, Jun 23, 1912.
  - 7. Bachman, Paul S., Feb 17, 1950.
  - 8. Baker, Jas. A., Apr 12, 1918.
  - 9. Baldensperger, Fernand, Jun 26, 1935.
  - 10. Baldensperger, Fernand, Oct 8, 1935.
  - 11. Baldensperger, Fernand, Oct 6, 1936.
  - 12. Baldensperger, Fernand, Mar 15, 1938.
  - 13. Baldensperger, Fernand, Apr 3, 1938.
  - 14. Baldensperger, Fernand, Apr 9, 1939.
  - 15. Baldensperger, Fernand, Feb 22, 1940.
  - 16. Baldensperger, Fernand, Oct 29, 1940.
  - 17. Baldensperger, Fernand, Nov 5, 1941.
  - 18. Baldensperger, Fernand, Apr 19, 1942.
  - 19. Barres, Maurice, Nov 22, 1918.
  - 20. Barzun, Jacques, Sept 6, 1937.
  - 21. Barzun, Jacques, Sept 30, 1940.
  - 22. Barzun, Jacques, Oct 21, 1940.
  - 23. Beals, Carleton, Aug 15, 1931.
  - 24. Becker, Carl, Oct 25, 1924.
  - 25. Belaunde, Victor, Apr 9, 1929.
  - 26. Belaunde, Victor, Mar 9, 1930.
  - 27. Berenson, Bernard, Jan 12, 1949.
  - 28. Berenson, Bernard, Jan 12, 1951.
  - 29. Berenson, Bernard, Mar 31, 1951.
  - 30. Berenson, Bernard, Nov 18, 1951.
  - 31. Berenson, Bernard, Jun 2, 1952.
  - 32. Berenson, Bernard, Sep 18, 1953.
  - 33. Berenson, Bernard, Feb 7, 1954.
  - 34. Blayney, Linsey, N.D.
  - 35. Bodley, J.E., May 15, 1914.
  - 36. Boujou, Paul, Dec 2, 1928.
  - 37. Boujou, Paul, Dec 21, 1929.
  - 38. Black, Roger D., Jul 8, 1918.
  - 39. Brooks, Van Wyck, Nov 11, 1932.
  - 40. Brooks, Van Wyck, Jun 18, 1935.
  - 41. Brooks, Van Wyck, Jan 18, 1936.
  - 42. Brooks, Van Wyck, Aug 17, 1936.
  - 43. Brooks, Van Wyck, Sep 4, 1936.
  - 44. Brooks, Van Wyck, Nov 14, 1938.
  - 45. Brooks, Van Wyck, Nov 6, 1951.
  - 46. Bryce, James, Aug 29, 1921.
  - 47. Brogan, D.W., Sept 8, 1942.
  - 48. Brogan, D.W., Dec 10, 1942.
  - 49. Brogan, D. W., Feb 3, 1943.
  - 50. Brogan, D. W., Apr 14, 1943.
  - 51. Brogan, D. W., Aug 24, 1943.
  - 52. Brogan, D. W., Oct 20, 1943.
  - 53. Buell, Raymond L., May 24, 1945.
  - 54. Cabell, James Branch, Dec 13, 1935. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 55. Cabell, James Branch, Dec 22, 1936.
  - 56. Cabell, James Branch, Nov 15, 1938.
  - 57. Cabell, James Branch, Apr 21, 1940.
  - 58. Cabell, James Branch, Dec 1, 1940.
  - 59. Cabell, James Branch, Apr 17, 1943.
  - 60. Cabell, James Branch, Oct 8, 1949.
  - 61. Cabell, James Branch, Sept 1, 1953.
  - 62. Cabell, James Branch, Oct 28, 1957.
  - 63. Camus, Albert, Mar 7, 1946.
  - 64. Carnup, Rudolf, Aug 7, 1939.
  - 65. Carnup, Rudolf, Jul 5, 1945.
  - 66. Cazamian, Louis, Apr 27, 1940.
  - 67. Cecil, Algernon, Sep 24, 1933.
  - 68. Charpenton, G., Jan 16, 1940.
  - 69. Cohn, Adolphe, Jan 22, 1916.
  - 70. Coldwell, Robert, Jan 4, 1929.
  - 71. Colune, Mary M., Jul 2, 1942.
  - 72. Coudenhove-Kalergi, Count Richard, Sep 10, 1943.
  - 73. Coudenhove-Kalergi, Count Richard, Jan 10, 1946.
  - 74. Culbertson, Ely, Jul 1, 1946.
  - 75. Delavenne, Georges, Aug 4, 1927.
  - 76. Dodd, William E., Jan 2, 1934.
  - 77. Deutsch, Monroe, Apr 30, 1938.
  - 78. Deutsch, Monroe, Apr 30, 1945.
  - 79. Dewey, John, May 18, 1917.
  - 80. Duclaux, Mary, Jul 10, 1918.
  - 81. Edman, Irwin, Nov 1, 1938.
  - 82. Edman, Irwin, Nov 3, 1938.
  - 83. Edman, Irwin, Jul 15, 1940.
- DIMNET LETTERS/MANUSCRIPT (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. Dinmet, Ernest, Mar 27, 1928.
    Scope and Contents note
    In French.
  - 2. Dinmet, Ernest, Mar 18, 1929.
  - 3. Dinmet, Ernest, N.D.
    In English.
  - 4. Dinmet, Ernest, Mar 24, (?).
  - 5. Dinmet, Ernest, Aug 13, (?).
  - 6. Dinmet, Ernest, May 31, (?).
  - 7. Dinmet, Ernest, N.D.
  - 8. Dinmet, Ernest, Jul 9, 1930.
    Fr & Eng
  - 9. Dinmet, Ernest, Feb 24, 1932.
  - 10. Dinmet, Ernest, Jun 30, 1932.
  - 11. Dinmet, Ernest, Sept 29, 1932.
  - 12. Dinmet, Ernest, Dec 13, 1932.
  - 13. Dinmet, Ernest, Feb 25, 1933.
  - 14. Dinmet, Ernest, Aug 6, 1933.
  - 15. Dinmet, Ernest, Nov 23, 1933.
  - 16. Dinmet, Ernest, Feb 7, 1934.
  - 17. Dinmet, Ernest, May 4, 1935.
  - 18. Dinmet, Ernest, Nov 9, 1935.
  - 19. Dinmet, Ernest, Nov 29, 1936.
  - 20. Dinmet, Ernest, Jan 3, 1938.
  - 21. Dinmet, Ernest, Mar 23 (?).
  - 22. Dinmet, Ernest, Jan 7 (?).
  - 23. Dinmet, Ernest, Apr 23, 1940.
  - 24. Dinmet, Ernest, Oct 2, 1945.
  - 25. Dinmet, Ernest, Nov 8, 1951.
  - 26. Dinmet, Ernest, Jun 10, 1953.
  - 27. Dinmet, Ernest, Jun 15, 1954.
  - 28. Dinmet, Ernest, Mar 21, (?).
  - 29. Dinmet, Ernest, Aug 14, (?).
  - 30. Dinmet, Ernest, Sep 14, (?).
  - 31. Dinmet, Ernest, Jul 29, (?).
  - 32. Dinmet, Ernest, Oct 6, (?).
  - 33. Dinmet, Ernest, N.D.
    (on United States Lines, “Manhattan”) In French.
  - 34. Dinmet, Ernest, N.D.
    (on board S.S. “Chaplain”) In French.
  - 35. Dinmet, Ernest, Oct 22, (?).
  - 36. Dinmet, Ernest, Jul 12, (?).
  - 37. Dinmet, Ernest, N.D.
  - 38. Dinmet, Ernest, N.D.
  - 39. Dinmet, Ernest
    Manuscript by Ernest Dinmet, “On the Use of Globes”.
  - 1. Farrell, James T., May 9, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2. Farrell, James T., Jun 1, 1946.
  - 3. Farrell, James T., Jun 2, 1946.
  - 4. Farrell, James T., Jun 12, 1946.
  - 5. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Jun 29, 1943.
  - 6. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, May 22, 1948.
  - 7. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Feb 17, 1950.
  - 8. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Mar 10, 1950.
  - 9. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, May 3, 1951.
  - 10. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Nov 13, 1951.
  - 11. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Jan 7, 1952.
  - 12. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Jan 14, 1952.
  - 13. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Dec 8, 1956.
  - 14. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Dec 27, 1956.
  - 15. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Jan 19, 1957.
  - 16. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Jan 30, 1957.
  - 17. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Feb 18, 1957.
  - 18. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Mar 7, 1957.
  - 19. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Mar 15, 1957.
  - 20. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Sep 13, 1957.
  - 21. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Oct 1, 1957.
  - 22. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Oct 7, 1957.
  - 23. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Nov 12, 1957.
  - 24. Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, Nov 29, 1957.
  - 25. Flexner, Abraham, Dec 1, 1930.
  - 26. Flexner, Abraham, Apr 10, 1931.
  - 27. Flexner, Abraham, Jun 4, 1931.
  - 28. Foerster, Norman, Feb 17, 1930.
  - 29. Frank, Waldo, Jan 28, 1957.
  - 30. Frank, Waldo, Feb 13, 1957.
  - 31. Frovic, O.M. (?), Nov 12, 1940.
  - 32. Galantiere, Lewis, Oct 13, 1939.
  - 33. Galantiere, Lewis, May 1, 1940.
  - 34. Galantiere, Lewis, Apr 8, 1940.
  - 35. Galantiere, Lewis, Jun 6, 1940.
  - 36. Gauss, Christian, Nov 20, 1933.
  - 37. Gauss, Christian, Oct 31, 1940.
  - 38. Glasgow, Ellen, Dec 14, 1940.
  - 39. Glasgow, Ellen, Oct 9, 1943.
  - 40. Green, Julien, Oct 5, 1942.
  - 41. Green, Julien, Sept 17, 1943.
  - 42. Gaxotte, Pierre, N.D.
  - 43. Gorman, Herbert, N.D.
  - 44. Harvey, John, Dec 14, 1929.
  - 45. Harvey, John, Jan 4, 1930.
  - 46. Harvey, John, Mar 1, 1930.
  - 47. Hazard, Paul, Aug 19, 1919.
  - 48. Hegemann, Werner, May 27, 1931.
  - 49. Hegemann, Werner, Jan 3, 1932.
  - 50. Hegeman, Werner, Oct 22, 1932. (Box 1, Folder 4 b)
  - 51. Hillyer, Robert, Oct 23, 1935.
  - 52. Hillyer, Robert, Jun 23, 1938.
  - 53. Hogben, Lancelot, Dec 8, 1939.
  - 54. Holmes, John Haynes, Apr 24, 1940.
  - 55. Holmes, John Haynes, May 10, 1940.
  - 56. Hoover, Herbert, Sep 22, 1941.
  - 57. Hoover, Herbert, Sep 6, 1943.
  - 58. Holley, Horace, Oct 31, 1930.
  - 59. Holley, Horace, Nov 26, 1930.
  - 60. House, E.M. (Col), Dec 31, 1918.
  - 61. Hubbell, Jay B., Jul 23, 1924.
  - 62. Huxley, Julian S., Dec 23, 1916.
  - 63. Huxley, Julian S., Aug 23, 1917.
  - 64. Huxley, Julian S., Apr 1, 1918.
  - 65. Huxley, Julian S., Oct 30, 1918.
  - 66. Huxley, Julian S., Mar 22, 1919.
  - 67. Huxley, Julian S., May 26, 1931.
  - 68. Huxley, Julian S., Mar 5, 1932.
  - 69. Huxley, Julian S., Oct 27, 1932.
  - 70. Huxley, Julian S., Nov 6, 1932.
  - 71. Huxley, Julian S., Nov 14, 1932.
  - 72. Huxley, Julian S., Nov 23, 1932.
  - 73. Huxley, Julian S., Jul 24, 1933.
  - 74. Huxley, Julian S., N.D.
  - 75. Hyde, James H., Nov 24, 1908.
  - 76. Unknown
  - Guérard, [UNK] to Chers [UNK], Sept. 30, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 4a.)
    LS in French by one of Guérard's aunts [UNK] his [Grandparents] to sent by balloon.
    Explanatory A.L.S. by Mrs. [UNK].
  - 1. Jezierski, Wieslaw, Jan 16, 1928. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2. Josephson, Matthew, Apr 19, 1931.
  - 3. Jusserand, Jules, Jan 28, 1913.
  - 4. Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.
    - a) Barnes, Harry E., Mar 31, 1926.
    - b)??, Harry C., Apr 23, 1926.
    - c) Knopf, Alfred A?, May 1, 1926.
    - d) Knopf, Alfred A?, May 11, 1926.
  - 5. Kohn, Hans, Mar 3, 1940.
  - 6. Kohn, Hans, Apr 10, 1940.
  - 7. Krutch, Joseph Wood, Oct 17, 1958.
  - 8. Lattimore, Owen, Nov 19, 1951.
  - 9. Lejouis, Emile, Mar 3, 1925.
  - 10. Lejouis, Emile, Apr 27, 1928.
  - 11. Lejouis, Emile, Dec 30, 1936.
  - 12. Lin Yutang, Jul 31, 1942.
  - 13. Lin Yutang, Aug 1, 1943.
  - 14. Luce, Henry B., Jun 6, 1940.
  - 15. Mann, Thomas, Oct 29, 1940.
  - 16. Mann, Thomas, Jan 25, 1946.
  - 17. Mann, Thomas, Apr 23, 1948.
  - 18. Mann, Thomas, Nov 5, 1948.
  - 19. Mann, Thomas, May 10, 1954.
  - 20. [copy of above], May 10, 1954.
  - 21. Maritain, Jacques, Dec 11, 1943.
  - 22. Mattingly, Garritt, Jun 21, 1958.
  - 23. Mattingly, Garritt, Jul 27, 1958.
  - 24. Maurois, Andre, Jul 29, 1942.
  - 25. McKay, Donald C., Jun 12, 1942.
  - 26. Minabrea, Andre, Jul 4, 1929.
  - 27. Minabrea, Andre, Dec 11, 1929.
  - 28. Minabrea, Andre, Jan 30, 1930.
  - 29. Minabrea, Andre, Jan 3, 1939.
  - 30. Mencken, H.L., Feb 22, 1929.
  - 31. Mencken, H.L., Dec 12, 1931.
  - 32. Mencken, H.L., Nov 30, 1932.
  - 33. Mencken, H.L., Dec 28, 1932.
  - 34. Mencken, H.L., Apr 16, 1932.
  - 35. Mencken, H.L., Jan 8, 1945.
  - 36. Milles, Walter, Feb 16, 1939.
  - 37. Milles, Walter, Nov 24, 1942.
  - 38. Milles, Walter, Jan 3, 1957.
  - 39. Mille, Pierre, May 2, 1938.
  - 40. Monaghan, Frank, May 15, 1931.
  - 41. Monaghan, Frank, Aug 30, 1931.
  - 42. Moore, Ernest C., Feb 4, 1929.
  - 43. Moore, Ernest C., Jul 16, 1931.
  - 44. Morand, Ruth, Sep 17, 1931.
  - 45. Mowrer, Edgard A., May 2, 1934.
  - 46. Mowrer, Edgard A., Dec 8, 1945.
  - 47. Mumford, Lewis, Apr 28, 1923.
  - 48. Mumford, Lewis, Nov 19, 1929.
  - 49. Mumford, Lewis, Oct 25, 1940.
  - 50. Mumford, Lewis, Dec 31, 1953.
  - 51. Mumford, Lewis, Aug 8, 1954.
  - 52. Munroe, William B., Oct 29, 1928.
  - 53. Munroe, William B., Sep 18, 1930.
  - 54. Munroe, William B., May 27, 1931.
  - 55. Maurois, Andre, Sep 10,?
  - 56. Maurois, Andre, Sep 15,?
  - 57. Maurois, Andre
  - 58. Mencken, H.L., Mar 30,?
  - 59. Mencken, H.L., Jul 21,?
  - 60. Mencken, H.L., Feb 8,?
  - 61. Mencken, H.L., N.D.
- DAVID STARR JORDAN CORRESPONDENCE (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1. Jordan, David Starr, Aug 26, 1909.
  - 2. Jordan, David Starr, Sep 16, 1909.
  - 3. Jordan, David Starr, May 10, 1910.
  - 4. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 15, 1911.
  - 5. Jordan, David Starr, Jul 17, 1911.
  - 6. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 20, 1911.
  - 7. Jordan, David Starr, Jun 15, 1913.
  - 8. Jordan, David Starr, Jun 25, 1913.
  - 9. Jordan, David Starr, Jul 26, 1913.
  - 10. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 29, 1913.
  - 11. Jordan, David Starr, Dec 31, 1913.
  - 12. Jordan, David Starr, Mar 22, 1914.
  - 13. Jordan, David Starr, Mar 23, 1914.
  - 14. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 10, 1914.
  - 15. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 21, 1914.
  - 16. Jordan, David Starr, Jun 11, 1914.
  - 17. Jordan, David Starr, Jul 13, 1914.
  - 18. Jordan, David Starr, Jul 23, 1914.
  - 19. Jordan, David Starr, Aug 22, 1914.
  - 20. Jordan, David Starr, Sep 2, 1914.
  - 21. Jordan, David Starr, Sep 17, 1914.
  - 22. Jordan, David Starr, Oct 7, 1914.
  - 23. Jordan, David Starr, Oct 23, 1914.
  - 24. Jordan, David Starr, Jan 11, 1915.
  - 25. Jordan, David Starr, Feb 24, 1915.
  - 26. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 6, 1915.
  - 27. Jordan, David Starr, July 7, 1915.
  - 28. Jordan, David Starr, Jul 31, 1915.
  - 29. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 29, 1915.
  - 30. Jordan, David Starr, Dec 15, 1915.
  - 31. Jordan, David Starr, Dec 27, 1915.
  - 32. Jordan, David Starr, Feb 3, 1916.
  - 33. Jordan, David Starr, Feb 10, 1916.
  - 34. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 14, 1916.
  - 35. Jordan, David Starr, Dec 16, 1916.
  - 36. Jordan, David Starr, Jan 30, 1917.
  - 37. Jordan, David Starr, Jan 31, 1917.
  - 38. Jordan, David Starr, Feb 10, 1917.
  - 39. Jordan, David Starr, Mar 7, 1917.
  - 40. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 1, 1917.
  - 41. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 14, 1917.
  - 42. Jordan, David Starr, May 23, 1917.
  - 43. Jordan, David Starr, Jun 18, 1917.
  - 44. Jordan, David Starr, Jul 24, 1917.
  - 45. Jordan, David Starr, Aug 23, 1917.
  - 46. Jordan, David Starr, Sep 12, 1917.
    Remarks by Guérard on back of letter.
  - 47. Jordan, David Starr, Aug 23, 1918.
  - 48. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 16, 1918.
  - 49. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 30, 1918.
  - 50. Jordan, David Starr, Jan 10, 1919.
  - 51. Jordan, David Starr, Jan 31, 1919.
  - 52. Jordan, David Starr, Apr 13, 1920.
  - 53. Jordan, David Starr, May 29, 1920.
  - 54. Jordan, David Starr, Jan 15, 1921.
  - 55. Jordan, David Starr, Feb 19, 1924.
  - 56. Jordan, David Starr, Feb 3, 1925.
  - 57. Jordan, David Starr, Mar 26, 1925.
  - 58. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 24, 1925.
  - 59. Jordan, David Starr, Jun 29, 1926.
  - 60. Jordan, David Starr, May 5, 1928.
  - 61. Jordan, David Starr, Jun 13, 1928.
  - 62. Jordan, David Starr, Nov 15, 1928.
  - 63. Jordan, David Starr
  - 64. Jordan, David Starr
    Poem by David Starr Jordan
  - 1. Nathan, George Jean, Mar 18, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 2. Nickerson, Hoffman, Oct 2, 1939.
  - 3. Nickerson, Hoffman, Oct 17, 1939.
  - 4. Nickerson, Hoffman, Oct 30, 1939.
  - 5. Nicolson, Harold, Feb 25, 1958.
  - 6. Niebuhr, Reinhold, Feb 23, 1943.
  - 7. Niebuhr, Reinhold, Jun 11, 1954.
  - 8. Niebuhr, Reinhold, Nov 21, 1955.
  - 9. Noyes, Alfred, Nov 9, 1936.
  - 10. Ogden, C.K., Mar 3, 1932.
  - 11. Parsons, Edward L., Jun 3, 1940.
  - 12. Parsons, Edward L., Sep 29, 1954.
  - 13. Parsons, Edward L., Mar 16, 1957.
  - 14. Parsons, Edward L., Feb 20, 1958.
  - 15. Parsons, Edward L., Dec 18, 1958.
  - 16. Parsons, Edward L., Jun 19, 1959.
  - 17. Parsons, Edward L., Jul 1, 1959.
  - 18. Parsons to Mrs. Guérard, Apr 21, 1960.
  - 19. Peano, Giuseppe, Feb 20, 1927.
  - 20. Peano, Giuseppe, Feb 26, 1927.
  - 21. (postcard), Nov 16, 1930.
  - 22. Pei, Mario, Oct 16, 1958.
  - 23. Perry, Bliss, Dec 7, 1951.
  - 24. Peyre, Henri M., Apr 22, 1942.
  - 25. Peyre, Henri M., Jun 18, 1943.
  - 26. Peyre, Henri M., Jul 19, 1943.
  - 27. Peyre, Henri M., Nov 13, 1944.
  - 28. Peyre, Henri M., Jun 26, 1945.
  - 29. Peyre, Henri M., Oct 6, 1945.
  - 30. Peyre, Henri M., Nov 9, 1945.
  - 31. Peyre, Henri M., May 31, 1946.
  - 32. Peyre, Henri M., Jun 19, 1946.
  - 33. Phelps, W. Lyon, Apr 28, 1924.
  - 34. Rostand, Edouard (card), ??, 1918.
  - 35. Rostand, Edouard (card), Jul 14, 1918.
  - 36. de Rougemont, Denis, Jan 3, 1943.
  - 37. Rowell, Chester H., Jun 10, 1930.
  - 38. Rowell, Chester H., Jul 5, 1932.
  - 39. Rowell, Chester H., Jul 9, 1932.
  - 40. Roz, Firmin, May 21, 1931.
  - 41. Russell, Bertrand, Nov 23, 1940.
  - 42. Peyre, Henri M., N.D.
  - 43. Polyzardes, Adamantios, Jan 16,?
  - 44. de Richemont, Viscount F., Dec 2,?
  - 1. Sabotier, Paul, Feb 9, 1913. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 2. Sabotier, Paul, Nov 7, 1916.
  - 3. Sait, Edward M., Jan 1, 1931.
  - 4. Schuman, Frederick L., Dec 12, 1952.
  - 5. Sedgwick, Ellery, Aug 26, 1931.
  - 6. Sedgwick, Ellery, Oct 5, 1931.
  - 7. Shotwell, James T., Nov 25, 1926.
  - 8. Siegfried, Andre, Jan 13, 1930.
  - 9. Siegfried, Andre, Feb 28, 1930.
  - 10. Siegfried, Andre, Jan 16, 1933.
  - 11. Siegfried, Andre, Sep 19, 1935.
  - 12. Siegfried, Andre, Feb 27, 1936.
  - 13. Siegfried, Andre, Apr 11, 1938.
  - 14. Siegfried, Andre, May 6, 1940.
  - 15. Siegfried, Andre, Nov 30, 1946.
  - 16. Siegfried, Andre, Apr 27, 1948.
  - 17. Siegfried, Andre, Jul 19, 1950.
  - 18. Siegfried, Andre, Jan 25, 1952.
  - 19. Siegfried, Andre, Oct 6,?
  - 20. Siegfried, Andre, Oct 28,?
  - 21. Siegfried, Andre, Jan 21,?
  - 22. Siegfried, Andre, Dec 24,?
  - 23. Simonds, Frank, May 4, 1932.
  - 24. Sloane, William, May 5, 1942.
  - 25. Sloane, William, Oct 27, 1952.
  - 23. de St. Maurice, A.B., Apr 29, 1929.
  - 24. Steegmuller, Francis, Oct 17, 1940.
  - 25. Steegmuller, Francis, Oct 26, 1940.
  - 26. Steegmuller, Francis, Feb 5, 1950.
  - 27. Stilling, Clark E., May 29, 1940.
  - 28. Stilling, Clark E., Jun 4, 1940.
  - 29. Stilling, Clark E., Jun 19, 1940.
  - 30. Strachey, Lytton, Aug 22, 1924.
  - 31. Swing, Raymond, Mar 9, 1940.
  - 32. Swing, Raymond, Aug 22,?
  - 33. Swing, Raymond, Oct 21, 1958.
  - 34. Swing, Raymond, Dec 1,?
  - 35. Sforza [Carlo?], May 15, 1942.
  - 36. Tempest, James, Aug 18, 1941.
  - 37. Thompson, Dorothy, Dec 26, 1944.
  - 38. Thompson, Dorothy, Jul 30, 1945.
  - 39. Thompson, Dorothy
  - 40. Vallaux, Camille, Nov 5, 1929.
  - 41. Vallaux, Camille, Sep 10, 1930.
  - 42. Van Doren, Mark, Sep 30, 1942.
  - 43. Van Doren, Mark, Oct 29, 1951.
  - 44. Van Loon, Hyndrick W., Sep 30, 1942.
  - 45. Van Loon, Hyndrick W., Oct 5, 1942.
  - 46. Vansittart, Lord Robt. G., Aug 25, 1945.
  - 47. Vansittart, Lord Robt. G., Sep 14, 1945.
  - 48. Vidalene, George, Mar 30, 1929.
  - 49. Villard, Oswald Garrison, Mar 29, 1932.
  - 50. Vincent, Daniel, Nov 10, 1930.
  - 51. Wells, H.G. (card), N.D.
  - 52. Weil, Bruno, Dec 9, 1931.
  - 53. Weil, Bruno, Jan 15, 1932.
  - 54. Whitlock, Brand, Nov 19, 1929.
  - 55. Wilbur, Ray Lyman, Apr 20, 1917.
  - 56. Wilson, Edmund, Mar 29, 1938.
  - 57. Wooley, Edgar Montillion (Monty Wooley), Jun 5, 1946.
  - 58. Wylie, Lawrence, Apr 24, 1957.
  - 59. Unknown, Aug 14, 1940.
- Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, 14 Jun 23 to 29 Jul 32. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Jun 14, 1923.
  - 2. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Jan 22, 1924.
  - 3. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Feb 11, 1924.
  - 4. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Aug 8, 1924.
  - 5. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Oct 2, 1924.
  - 6. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Oct 18, 1924.
  - 7. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Mar 16, 1925.
  - 8. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Nov 9, 1926.
  - 9. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Dec 9, 1927.
  - 10. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Mar 28, 1927.
  - 11. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Feb 25, 1930.
  - 12. Guérard - CHARLES SCRIBNER & SONS, Jul 29, 1932.
- Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jan 7, 1914.
  - 2. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jan 24, 1914.
  - 3. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Feb 3, 1914.
  - 4. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Mar 5, 1914.
  - 5. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Mar 30, 1914.
  - 6. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jul 25, 1914.
  - 7. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jul 31, 1914.
  - 8. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Sep 4, 1914.
  - 9. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Oct 7, 1914.
  - 10. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 30, 1914.
  - 11. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Jun 11, 1915.
  - 12. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Sep 28, 1915.
  - 13. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Nov 4, 1915.
  - 14. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Dec 7, 1915.
  - 15. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Feb 15, 1916.
  - 16. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Mar 7, 1916.
  - 17. Guérard - T. FISHER IRWIN [Publishers, England], Mar 23, 1916.